Resume

Personal

Name Surname

Nationality / Resident

Passport No.

Permanent address

D.O.B. / Place Martial status Cell / Fixed E. Mail RAJESH Kalra

Indian / Moroccan

Z - 1518536

Block - E, # 18, Plage Johara,

Skhirat, Morocco.

February 26th, 1963, Nashik Married / Children (20 & 9 yrs.) + 212 6482 6452 / + 212 3774 9352 rajesch kalra@hotmail.com

Objective

Interested to seek long term commitment position; as CEO / Project Manager / Country Director with any tourism or construction related organization of international repute in Morocco.

Availability w.e.f. 15th September 2007 and travel availability up to 70% to any part of the world with readiness to accept even 'level four' risk factor challenges.

Demonstrable polyvalent expertise & perquisite experience in UN project management (construction & health) fund raising / management system logistics / system quality; having handled top management responsibility as a Country Director & Consultant in various African countries. Preference can also be given to Purchases Quality Mgt. & Logistical management related jobs.

Capability

Having qualifications like Bachelor of Commerce (Management & Accountancy) & a Double MBA (Marketing & Personnel Management), including high level technical knowledge of Mechanical & Civil Engineering projects with vocational specializing in Small Scale Industries & Self Employment besides expertise in most MIS computing languages.

Excellent understanding of project budget computation task charts logistical planning and real time monitoring tools throughout the project cycle, audit, tracking and performance reporting.

Exceptionally very long association consistent track record with very few changes of carrier, currently has resigned from the post of Country Director from the UN sponsored biggest funded African NGO, having represented the organization to various UN stakeholders, NGOs, Government and Media.

Qualifications & Training

M. B. A. (2nd Masters)

Personnel Management University of Pune, India

1986

 Double Masters in Business Administration specializing in Personnel Management with special emphasis on human resource development & performance appraisal.

M. B. A. (Masters)

Marketing Management University of Pune, India

 Masters in Business Administration, specializing in Marketing Management & Research with additional training in Econometrics, Accountancy & Financial Systems Management.

B. Com. Business Administration University of Pune, India 1977

 Bachelor of Commerce, with in depth study of Economics, Accountancy, Human Resources Development & Management., Principals and Practices of Management.

FY / SYJC (High School) Small Scale Industries & University of Pune, India 1976

Self-Employment

Vocational training in Micro Finance, Small Scale Industrial Development & Self Employment

Languages

English Fluent & (Excellence in projects, contracts & bid drafting)

French Intermediate
Hindi Fluent
Punjabi Native
Marathi Fluent
Gujrathi Fluent
Swahili Basic
Amharic Basic

Informatics

Microsoft: Word / Excel / Visio / Outlook / Explorer / MS Works & Mostly all MIS Languages

Programming & GPS: Visual basic & Map Source Photo Management: Photoshop / Picassa 2

Finance: UN SPMR reporting system software & Tally

Employment

Country Director – Republic of Chad (Refugee Host Community Support Program) Organization Name: Africa Humanitarian Action (UNHCR funded biggest African NGO) 05/06 - 07/07

- Independently launched a new remote programme in Chad participated in bids drafted many proposals; promoted the new NGO to the Govt. & local authorities through networking & Single handedly registered the NGO, Fund raised, established three offices across the country, hired and contracted human resources and efficiently run the NGO with minimal of resources and completed four projects,
- Direct responsibility of project proposal preparation UN ECHO fund raised amounting \$.8 Million for UNHCR Hajer Hadid WATSAN project for Host Community Population support. Project technically conceptualized, logistically managed & executed.
- Assisted WFP Logistical assistance to build WFP Office & Guest house during heavy rains in war torn Gozbeida region of Chad.
- Negotiated with host population and constructed one primary schools & one health centre in the war torn border regions of Goz Beida alongside Sudan and Central African Republic border.
- Successful project management during civil war, elections, a racially tense and violent period on the border regions of Abeche.
- Successfully managed staffing issues including tribal tensions and local disputes.
- · Independently fund raised from local population & businessmen to help a

primary school repair its premises, constructed kitchen and toilets assisting school children in Hajer Hadid.

Country Director – Republic of Guinea

03/04 - 04/06

(Liberia & Sierra Leone Civil War IDP & Urban Refugee Health Care)

Organization Name: Africa Humanitarian Action

- Humanitarian project development & IDP health care clinic management for 100 patients OPD / daily + 120 patients hospitalization in Guinea for Liberian & Sierra Leonean refugees,
- Disaster needs assessment & SOS project execution with technical expertise recommendations granted for Algeria earthquake victims,
- Conducted a Seminar for the Prime Minister's Office for Enhancing the Capacity Building of the Government of Guinea and got the NGO appointed as the consultant to the Government.
- Successfully fund raised, project planning, management and report-writing for UNHCR – ECHO projects,
- International Logistical project execution for Liberia civil war refugees for health care and agro projects,
- Bold & determinately resolved refugee conflicts having negotiated with mediation in adverse national situation,
- Successfully managed staffing issues including legal battle against the NGO and staff harassment by the previously managed project staff.
- Recruited Human resources, Framed & Managed strategic policies for more than 35 medical staff members, Adapted & responded to demands and developments concerning project progress,
- Conducted on time successful International S.O.S. Para-medical & Pharmaceutical purchases logistical operations including clearing of goods,
- Experience gained in disaster mission mgt. skills & humanitarian needs assessment having managed Multi donor grant management, project reporting, assessment, & liaison with success in Guinea,
- Educated medical staff members in Computer application & Informatics; an Individual Capacity Building initiative project completed with positive outlook & stand-alone disposition.

CEO (Secretary General) - Kingdom of Morocco

01/01 - 02/03

Africa's major Copper Recycling and Copper Tubes Manufacturing Industry

Organization Name: MAC//Z Tubes En Cuivre

- Was appointed as Director of Human Resources management & development,
- ISO 9002 system quality management constitution and application project handled independently,
- Headed the Purchase Department, Management Information Systems networking was established as an additional charge responsible of the Informatics department,
- Commenced operations as a Consultant, reporting to the Director General assistance was provided for sick unit rehabilitation, and managed to revitalize the sick unit on to main track. With more than 250 employees.

Faculty Professor (PT): Rabat - Kingdom Of Morocco

2000 - 2003

University Of Texas Affiliated American School & Professional Mgt. Training

Organization Name: I.I.H.E.M International Institute of Higher Education in Morocco

 With an objective to refresh knowledge taught students to gain teaching expertise in subjects like Marketing, Logistics, Advertising, Sales & Human Resources Management to Professionals, Post graduate & Graduate students developing high Communication skills and teaching experience, Competent of conducting motivational seminars for Multinational organizations for management objectives or Logistics Mgt. education.

Entrepreneur Proprietor: Consulting Company – Republic of Ethiopia 1997 - 1999

N.G.O. & Industrial - Consulting Company Organization Name: Solution Consultants

 Successfully completed Procurement & Logistical Operations for 1994 -Genocide disaster relief paramedical health centers for AHA / UNHCR refugee camps in Rwanda & Democratic Republic of Congo,

• Consulting company catering to NGO's logistics & procurement, besides prospecting bilateral trade between India & Africa since 1994.

Entrepreneur Proprietor: Trading Company – Republic of India Wholesale MNC Consumer Products Trading Company Organization Name: RK Distributors & RK Consultants

1987-1996

- From conception to establishment of exclusive wholesale Selling agent of Mattel Toys, Eagle Flasks, Trans Electra, & many reputed consumer & white good's brands.
- Sugar Industry machinery foundation civil construction contractors.

Countries Traveled

 Algeria, Benin, Burundi Cameroon, Chad, Democratic Republic of Congo, Ethiopia, France, Germany, Ghana, Guinea, India, Italy, Kenya, Mali, Mauritius, Morocco, Niger, Nepal, Rwanda, Senegal, Singapore, Spain, Uganda & Zambia.

References

- H.E. Ambassador Mr. Prabhu Dayal, Ambassador of India, Rabat, Morocco. Cell: +212 61 14 41 00
- Mr. Adnane Lamdouar, CEO & Director General, Mac//z Tubes En Cuivre, Skhirat, Rabat, Morocco. Cell: +212 63 01 10 62

Also

Possessing a valid International Driving Permit of L.C.V. & M.C.

Resume

Personal

Name Surname

Nationality / Resident Passport No.

Permanent address

D.O.B. / Place **Martial status** Cell / Fixed E. Mail

RAJESH Kalra

Indian / Moroccan

Z - 1518536

Block - E, # 18, Plage Johara,

Skhirat, Morocco.

February 26th, 1963, Nashik Married / Children (20 & 9 yrs.) + 212 6482 6452 / + 212 3774 9352 raiesch kalra@hotmail.com

Objective

Interested to seek long term position; as the Country Director / Project Manager / Consultant or CEO with an N.G.O. or Organization of international repute.

Availability w.e.f October 2007 to relocate in any part of the world with readiness to accept even high risk factor challenges.

Demonstrable polyvalent expertise & perquisite experience in UN project fund raising / management / accounting system management; having handled top management responsibility as a Country Director & Consultant in various African countries.

Capability

Having qualifications like Bachelor of Commerce (Management & Accountancy) & a Double MBA (Marketing & Personnel Management), including high level technical knowledge of Mechanical & Civil Engineering projects with vocational specializing in Small Scale Industries & Self Employment besides expertise in most MIS computing languages.

Excellent understanding of project budget computation task charts logistical planning and real time monitoring tools throughout the project cycle, audit, tracking and performance reporting.

Exceptionally very long association consistent track record with very few changes of carrier, currently has resigned from the post of Country Director from the UN sponsored biggest funded African NGO, having represented the organization to various UN stakeholders, NGOs, Government and Media.

Qualifications & Training

M. B. A. (2nd Masters)

Personnel Management University of Pune, India

1986

Double Masters in Business Administration specializing in Personnel Management with special emphasis on human resource development & performance appraisal.

M. B. A. (Masters)

Marketing Management University of Pune, India

1984

Masters in Business Administration, specializing in Marketing Management & Research with additional training in Econometrics, Accountancy & Financial Systems Management.

B. Com.

Business Administration University of Pune, India